当时正是一八九一年
The year was 1891.
欧洲的局势阴云密布
Storm clouds were brewing over Europe.
法德两国成剑拔弩张之势
France and Germany were at each other's throats…
都由那一系列的爆炸案引起
…the result of a series of bombings.
有人说是民族主义者的作为
Some said it was Nationalists…
也有说是无政府主义者
…others, the anarchists.
当然 我的朋友 夏洛克·福尔摩斯
But as usual…my friend Sherlock Holmes …
他的理论依旧与众不同
…had a different theory entirely.
斯特拉斯堡发生爆炸 号外号外
Bombing in Strasbourg! Read all about it!
谢谢
Thank you.
无政府主义者涉嫌斯特拉斯堡爆炸案
Anarchists suspected…in Strasbourg bombing!
你什么时候开始当邮递员了
When did you start working for the postal service?
那个人是你啊
That was you back there.
破案破到这个地步还真倒楣
Shame your activities have landed you in the gutter.
包裹很可疑 敢问收件人是哪位
A curious parcel.Who's the intended recipient?
不如等晚上吃饭时候再聊吧
Why don't we discuss that over dinner tonight?
午饭我有空
I'm free for lunch.
可我没空
Hmm. I'm not.
萨沃伊餐厅怎么样 晚上八点
How about the Savoy, 8:00?
正合我意
Splendid.
到时候你会现出原形吗
And will you be coming as yourself?
很有可能
Most likely.
有三个人跟踪了我们半英里路
Three men have been following you for the last half mile…
他们动机相当不单纯
…their motives highly unsavory.
不好
No.
对了 他们不是在追我 而是在护送我
Oh, and, by the way, they're not pursuing me, they're escorting me.
而且好像不止三个人 应该有四个
And instead of three, there seems to be, uh, four.
要小心轻放 艾琳
Steady hands with that, Irene.
现在需要小心的人应该不是我
Oh, I don't think it's my hands you have to worry about.
别在脸上下重手 我们晚上还有约会
Be careful with the face, boys. We do have a dinner date tonight.
餐前面包少吃点
Don't fill up on bread.
后面我忘记了
I forgot the rest.
现在想起来了
Oh, it's coming back now.
有条子
Peelers!
现在开拍三十四号藏品
We now come to Lot 34…
一尊雕饰异常华丽的埃及石棺
…Egyptian sarcophagus of outstanding provenance…
发掘自国王峡谷
…retrieved from the Valley of the Kings.
你的报酬 大夫 他说非常感谢
Your payment, doctor. He sends his thanks.
谁愿意出价一百英镑
Who will bid 100 pounds?
一百英镑
One hundred. Thank you, sir.
请转交给他 他等着要的
Please, give this to him. He's expecting it.
就说那位朋友以为我把信给他姐姐了
Tell him our friend thinks I delivered it to his sister.
请坐
Uh… Stay…
等我看一下东西
…while I check the contents.
他说全部报酬都在这儿
I was assured full payment would be there.
是吧
Yes
但他又是谁呢
but assured by whom?
你有没有见过他本人
Have you ever met him in person?
还是像我一样
Or like me, have you been…
别动 别动 千万别动
Hold it, hold it. Please, don't move it.
根据尺寸和重量来看
Judging from size and weight,
这可不是你想要的报酬
it's not the payment you were expecting.
依我看这东西应该会相当劲爆
I'd wager the contents are rather more incendiary.
他是谁
Who is this?
他是
It's…
你好 亲爱的
Hello, darling.
哦 天哪 告诉过你不要动的
Oh, dear. I told you not to move it.
看来备用引爆器被激活了
It seems a secondary charge has been activated.
美女 我处理包裹的时候可能要你协助
Sweet thing, I might need your help in the disposal of this parcel.
一千六百英镑
One thousand six hundred,
一千七百英镑
1700￡,
一千八百英镑
1800￡.
祝你好运
Well, good luck.
一千九百英镑
1900￡.
一百万英镑
One million pounds.
哦 还有 着火了
Oh, and by the way, fire.
你要是逃走 一小时内必死无疑
Leave my side, you'll be dead in an hour.
记得晚饭不要迟到
And don't be late for dinner.
出了这种状况
My schedule will be quite tight
我接下来的行程会排得很满的
because of these activities here.
我这辈子从不迟到 只会提前
I've never been late in my life, only early.
很有品味
Fashionably.
非常狡猾 就算逃跑也那么自信
Very witty. So confident, even in retreat.
这个我来保管
I'II hold onto that.
等喝开胃酒的时候再一起看吧
We'll read it together over an aperitif.
好啊 边吃边看好戏
Fine. Dinner and a show.
等着 相信我 我是靠这个吃饭的
Stay. Trust me. This is what I do for a living.
赫尔·霍芬斯塔 你真的很走运
Herr Hoffmanstahl, you should count yourself lucky.
你替他办事的这神秘人物不是普通罪犯
This faceless man with whom you find yourself in business is no ordinary criminal.
他是个犯罪之王
He's the Napoleon of crime.
幸运的是 你现在有我这个盟友
Fortunately, you now have me as an ally.
我是个小有名气的私家侦探
I'm a consulting detective of some repute.
也许你听说过我 我的名字叫福尔
Perhaps you've heard of me? My name is Sherlock…
摩斯
…Holmes.
帮我换一杯茶 谢谢 乔治
A fresh pot of tea. Thank you, George.
好的 艾德勒小姐
Yes, Miss Adler.
选得不错 这个地方
Fine choice, this place.
信带来了吗
Do you have the letter?
它被拿走了
It was taken.
拿走了 那真是太不幸了
Taken? Now, that is unfortunate.
都是你包裹惹出来的麻烦
During the chaos created by your package.
谢谢
Thank you.
也许你该早点告诉我你的计划
Perhaps if you had shared your plans.
你想要知道我的计划 对吗
You wish to know my plans now, do you?
你在怀疑我会对你不利 艾德勒小姐
Did you imagine, Miss Adler, that something would happen to you?
所以才会把见面地点选在公共场合
Is that why you chose to meet here in a public place?
你最喜欢的餐厅
Your favorite restaurant?
这不怪你
I don't blame you.
都怪我自己
I blame myself.
我早就发现你没办法 控制住对他的感情
It's been apparent to me for some time that you had succumbed to your feelings for him.
这也不是福尔摩斯 第一次给我带来不便了
And this isn't the first occasion Mr. Holmes has inconvenienced me in recent months.
问题在于
The question is…
应该如何去应对
…what to do about it.
但是
But
现在这是我自己的问题
that's my problem to solve now.
我不再需要你的协助了
I no longer require your services.
《大侦探福尔摩斯2：诡影游戏》
哈德森夫人
Mrs. Hudson?
哈德森夫人在吗
Oh, Mrs. Hudson?
福尔摩斯 在家吗
Holmes, you in there?
你家篱笆该修剪了
Your hedge needs trimming.
你猜我在哪儿
Where am I?
我不管你在哪儿 准备好出门就行
I don't care where you are as long as you're ready.
我在等你
I'm waiting.
我不想玩捉迷藏
I'm not gonna play this game.
记得吗 我得赶上末班
Remember, I have to catch the last…
车
…train.
很不幸你死了
That's you dead, I'm afraid.
你赢了
You win.
我输了 游戏结束
I lose. Game over.
还没找到我吗
Still don't see me?
真是意外啊
穿成这样 我是不会和你出去的
I'm not going out with you dressed like that.
要不我和你一样穿上老掉牙的军外套
Would you prefer I joined you in the fashion faux pas…
围上一条恶心的手工围巾怎么样
…of wearing fine military dress with that heinous handmade scarf…
显然是你未婚妻的早期作品吧
…clearly one of your fianc'searly efforts?
我想死你了 福尔摩斯
Oh, how I've missed you, Holmes.
是吗
Have you?
为什么
Why?
我几乎没有注意到你走了
I've barely noticed your absence.
我一直专注于研究
Then again, I'm knee-deep in research.
从羊的肾上腺中提取液体
Extracting fluids from the adrenal glands of sheep…
设计我专用的都市迷彩服
…and designing my own urban camouflage…
同时步步逼近 我整个侦探生涯中
…all the while verging on a decisive breakthrough…
最重要的案子的决定性突破点
…in the single most important case of my career,
也许将永载史册
perhaps of all time.
哈德森夫人 你好啊
Mrs. Hudson, how are you?
见到你很高兴 大夫
Oh. I'm so pleased to see you, doctor.
谢谢你的邀请
Thank you for inviting me tomorrow.
我也很感谢你对爱犬的照料
And thank you for looking after Gladstone.
亲爱的热情过度的管家夫人 能说句话吗
Dear, dear sickly-sweet Nanny, might I have a word?
美味
Yummy.
你去喂蛇吧
Feed the snake, woman.
你去喂吧
You feed it.
妇人之仁
Touchy, touchy.
大夫 你必须送他去疗养院
Doctor, you must get him to a sanatorium.
他最近不是咖啡 烟草 就是可可汁
He's been on a diet of coffee, tobacco, and coca leaves.
他不睡觉了
He never sleeps.
整天南腔北调的就像在排练话剧
I hear multiple voices as if he's rehearsing a play.
我会处理的
Leave him to me.
你是不是该给山羊吃打虫药了
Don't you have a goat that needs worming?
谢谢你提醒我
Oh, how kind of you to remind me.
我都快等不及了
So much to look forward to.
没了你我该怎么办
What would I do without you?
祝你的病人顺利康复 大夫
Good luck with your patient, doctor.
你来干什么
Why are you here?
我明天就结婚了
I'm getting married tomorrow.
拥抱一下
Oh! Embrace me.
华生要结婚了
Watson's getting married.
你掉了几斤肉嘛 福尔摩斯
You've lost a few pounds, Holmes.
是啊 都到你身上去了
Yes, and you've picked them up.
肯定没少吃玛丽的松饼
Noshing on Mary's muffins, no doubt.
倒两杯白兰地
Pour us a brandy.
单身派对现在开始
The stag party has begun.
这是我们最后的冒险 华生
It is our last adventure, Watson.
我一定不会浪费的
I intend to make the most of it.
看来我以前的办公室也没浪费
I see you've made good use of my old office.
喜欢我的蜘蛛网吗
Do you like my spider's web?
怎么叫这名字
Is that what you call it?
你看那条线
Follow that strand.
请问
Question:
与印度棉花大亨有关的丑闻
What do a scandal involving an Indian cotton tycoon…
中国鸦片商人吸毒过量身亡
…the overdose of a Chinese opium trader…
斯特拉斯堡和维也纳爆炸案
…bombings in Strasbourg and Vienna…
以及美国钢铁巨头之死
…and the death of a steel magnate in America
都有什么共同点
all have in common?
根据你的立体模型来看
Well, according to your diorama,
是詹姆斯·莫里亚蒂教授
Professor James Moriarty.
一点没错
Indeed.
数学天才 著名作家和演讲家
Mathematical genius. Celebrated author and lecturer.
剑桥时代是拳击冠军
Boxing champion at Cambridge…
同时也与现任首相成了好朋友
…where he made friends with our current prime minister.
你有什么证据来支持你的观点吗
Do you have any evidence to substantiate your claim?
（炸弹危机化解 拍卖行逃过一劫）
这个
This.
现在明白了吗
Now do you see?
霍芬斯塔医生之死
Dr. Hoffmanstahl's death?
没错 我听你提过他 盛赞他的医德
Yes.I've heard you speak of him, extolling his virtues.
霍芬斯塔是医学创新前沿的开拓者
Hoffmanstahl was at the forefront of medical innovations, a true pioneer.
就在前不久
Just the other day,
我化解了一起针对他的炸弹袭击
I averted an explosion that was intended for him.
这里说他死于心脏病
Says here he died of a heart attack.
我的谆谆教诲都白费了吗
Has all my instruction been for naught?
你还在看官方报导而且居然会相信它
You read the official statement and believe it.
这是较量 老伙计 暗中的较量
It's a game, dear man, a shadowy game.
教授和我就像是猫和老鼠
We're playing cat and mouse, the professor and I.
斗篷和匕首
Cloak and dagger.
难道不是蜘蛛和苍蝇吗
I thought it was spider and fly?
（甲醛）
我才不是苍蝇 我是猫
I'm not a fly, I'm a cat.
不是老鼠 是匕首
Not a mouse, but a dagger.
你喝的是尸体防腐液
You're drinking embalming fluid.
是的 来一杯吗
Ooh. Yes. Care for a drop?
你是有点
You do seem…
- 兴奋 - 疯癫
- Excited? - Manic.
- 我承认 - 几乎近于
- I am. - Verging on…
- 神经质 - 神经病
- Ecstatic? - Psychotic.
我真该给你带点镇定剂
Should've brought a sedative.
我拼上性命也要扳倒他
I'II give my life to see his demise.
一定要在他的邪恶阴谋得逞之前阻止他
He must be stopped before his evil machinations come to a crescendo.
他怎么实施阴谋呢
And how will he do all this?
别那么无知 坏人就是做得出坏事
Don't be a dingy bird. Bad people do bad things because they can.
无论受害者 警察还是政府 没有人
No one, not the victims, the police, the governments, not anyone…
- 除了大侦探福尔摩斯 - 没错
- Except the great Sherlock Holmes… - Correct.
以这种状态
…on this diet,
才能破解迷局
will work it all out.
没错
Right.
八九不离十
Or thereabouts.
八九左右 还没到十
Thereabouts, not quite there.
祝你身体健康
Here's to your good health.
无知的家伙
Dingy bird.
你又对格莱斯顿做了什么
What have you done to Gladstone now?
是蓖麻 它的果实有剧毒
Ricinus communis. The fruit is highly toxic.
它快停止呼吸了
He's barely breathing.
真个绝妙的时机
What an excellent opportunity.
这东西应该有效
This may be just the thing.
你不介意我试验一下肾上腺提取物吧
Sorry, do you mind terribly if I try my adrenal extract?
我家的狗到底要死几次你才开心
How many times are you going to kill my dog, Holmes?
跑得像出笼的猴子一样快
Took off like a monkey from a box.
说不定我等一下会用到这东西
I may need one of those in a few hours.
就当作是结婚礼物吧
Consider it a wedding gift.
华生 我们从另一个门出去吧
Watson, might we use an alternative exit?
你的样子有变过吗
Is there something different about you?
我被人盯梢了
I'm under observation.
是该看住你
As you should be.
你来开车
You drive.
你打算整个晚上都带着胡子吗
Will your beard be with us all night?
等过了特拉法加广场我就摘下来
I'II remove it once we're south of Trafalgar Square.
如果莫里亚蒂的人在跟踪你的话
If you believe Moriarty has you under observation…
这样子是不是太显眼了
…isn't this a bit conspicuous?
高调到极致 就是隐蔽
It's so overt, it's covert.
特拉法加广场 你应该安全了
Trafalgar Square. You must be safe by now.
为什么你这么忧虑地看着我
Why are you looking at me with such concern?
因为我很担心你
I'm so very worried.
你的生命力都快干涸了
Your vitality's been drained from you.
婚姻是坟墓 我告诉你
Marriage is the end, I tell you.
我认为是个新开始
I think of it as the beginning.
世界末日
Armageddon.
重获新生
Rebirth.
一种束缚
Restriction.
一个归宿
Structure.
听女人的使唤
Answering to a woman.
经营一段感情
Being in a relationship.
和谐美满的生活
A life in matrimony,
还有共享天伦之乐
the possibility of a family.
谁愿意孤独终老
Who wants to die alone?
所以我们今天按照惯例彻夜狂欢
We'll have a good old-fashioned romp tonight…
然后你去结婚生子
…you'l settle down, have a family,
而我孤独终老
and I'II die alone.
差不多是这样
Yes, that's about it.
我想孤独终老至少也胜过
Perhaps it's better for one to die alone
一辈子活在人间地狱
than to live life in eternal purgatory.
随你便啦
Anyway…
灯还不错
Not bad, that.
我们要去哪儿
So where are we going?
未来这种机器会遍布欧洲的大街小巷
In the future, there'll be one of those machines in every town in Europe.
又在柴房里游荡了 是吗 迈克
Loitering in the woodshed again, are we, Myccie?
晚上好 歇利
Good evening, Sherly.
好
Well.
看来你的修鞋匠病了 亲爱的弟弟
I see your bootmaker is ill, dear brother.
我发觉你换了一个牌子的肥皂来刮胡子
As I detect that you've recently changed the brand of soap with which you shave.
我想说你贝克街前厅的烟囱
The chimney in the front room at Baker Street…
真的应该再好好打理一下才行
…still needs a damn good sweeping up.
你是否发现来时坐的马车有个轮子坏了
Were you aware that the hackney carriage by which you arrived had a damaged wheel?
当然 左轮
Yes, the left.
而且再笨的人也能猜到你最近给小提琴
And it's plain to the meanest intelligence…
买了把新琴弓
…that you have recently acquired a new bow for your violin.
老琴弓 新琴弦
Same bow, new strings.
如果我没猜错
And may I deduce, Mycroft…
迈克罗夫特 晚上好
Good evening, by the way.
免了
No.
他不握手
He doesn't.
依我之见像你这样一个
May I deduce that you…
不是在家就是在第欧根尼俱乐部
who rarely strays from the path that runs from your home to the Diogenes Club
而且从不错过每星期一小锅炒虾的人
…and never on a Monday when they serve your favorite potted shrimps…
来此必有比参加单身派对更重要的原因
…must be here for some far more important reason than my stag party?
我觉得他根本就不是你说的
You know, he's nothing like as slow-witted
那种智力低下的笨蛋 歇利
as you'd been leading me to believe, Sherly.
你说得很对 华生大夫
No, you're quite right, Dr. Watson…
眼下的欧洲暗流涌动 局势随时都可能
…but with all the conflict in Europe at the moment, the whole situation could…
请让一让
Excuse me.
一触即发
suddenly erupt.
我来这里是要阻止一场大灾难
I am here to avoid a dire catastrophe.
某两个国家关系很紧张
If the concerns of two nations…
我不能透露它们的名字
…which shall remain nameless…
但它们分别说的是法语和德语
…but I can tell you they speak French and German…
今晚若调解不好 我就不得不去瑞士
…are not dealt with tonight, I shall be forced to go to Switzerland…
参加在莱辛巴赫举行的和平峰会
…to attend the ghastly peace summit in Reichenbach.
瑞士最讨厌的就是海拔太高
The worst thing about Switzerland is the altitude.
又让我流鼻血又加重我的哮喘
It gives me nosebleeds, exacerbates my asthma…
我很高兴你邀请了你哥哥
I'm so glad you invited your brother.
看起来很不错
This looks promising.
想要喝点什么 先生们
And your poison of choice, gentlemen?
先从香槟开始吧
Well start with the champagne.
我们可能还要几把椅子
We may need several more chairs.
给我来一支雪茄
Perhaps a good cigar.
还有椅子就不必了
And don't bother with the chairs.
你哥哥究竟是干什么的
What is it your brother does exactly?
他是个给国家管管杂物的小干部
He's the keeper of the broom cupboard of state.
没野心 没激情 但我一直听人说
No ambition, no energy yet I'm repeatedly told that
英国政府好像没了他不行
he's indispensable to the British government…
尤其是外交部
…particularly the Foreign Office.
让我来敬你一杯
I would like to propose a toast.
是吗
Really?
敬我的好友 医生 约翰
To my dear friend, Dr. John…
哈密什 华生
…um, Hamish Watson…
我就在这儿
I'm right here.
在这婚礼的前夜
…on the eve of his wedding.
他
He…
是我最好的伙伴
…has been the best companion.
不要再等等吗
Shouldn't we be waiting
我在橄榄球队的兄弟们呢
for the boys from my rugby club?
他一直帮助我们
He has always kept us…
他们来不了了
They couldn't attend.
脚踏实地去生活
…flat-footed on the ground.
都没空吗 那我在医学院的那些同学呢
AII of them? Hmm. The chaps from my medical school?
我叫了 他们不来
They declined.
那军队里的战友呢
The lads from the regiment?
没有人比他更加
No man's better
那你到底在找谁
Who is it you're looking for?
值得你去结交
Worth having at your side…
因为这里我一个认识的人都没有 对吗
Because I don't know a single damn person here, do I?
你这么激动干什么
There's no need for hysterics.
你认识我 认识迈克罗夫特
You know me and Mycroft.
别那么饥渴 华生
Don't be a ponce, Watson.
饥渴
Ponce?
你完全忘了我的单身派对 是不是
You completely forgot about my stag party, didn't you?
来这里做什么
Why are we here?
祝你身体健康 大夫
Your very good health, doctor.
很遗憾你的朋友们都没来
Shame none of your friends could make it.
我要过去玩上几把
I'm going to the gaming tables.
我不能接受今晚就这么给毁了 把钱给我
I refuse for this night to be a total loss.Give me my money.
很乐意
Happily.
把结婚戒指给我
Give me the wedding ring.
现在怎么想起来自己是伴郎了
So now you're interested in being the best man.
戒指确实应该由你保管没错
You're supposed to keep the ring anyway.
组织单身派对也应该是你的责任
Just as you're supposed to organize my stag party.
我是担心你把戒指赔进去 约翰
Don't want to lose it on a bet.
还有邀请我的朋友们 我有不少朋友
And invite my friends …of which, by the way, there are many.
没有朋友的人是你 孤僻怪人
You're the one with no friends…Sherly No Mates.
这人真自以为是 对不对
He's all "me, me, me, " isn't he?
我赢了
I win!
请坐
Please, sit.
把钱放在桌上我们就开始
Put your money on the table and we will begin.
欢迎 我是西姆萨夫人
Welcome. I am Madam Simza.
牌能洞悉你的过去
Cards can illuminate your past…
看清你的现状 揭示你的未来
…clarify your present, and show you the future.
如果你想问什么问题 请在心中默念
If you have a specific question, hold it in your mind.
我正在默念
I'm holding.
准备好了告诉我
Let me know when you're ready.
说实话 我是想要算算
Actually, I'd prefer to read…
你的命
…your fortune.
节制
Temperance inverted.
逆位意味着反覆无常
Indicative of volatility.
一个女人最近整天借酒浇愁
A woman who has recently taken her comfort in drink.
她在寻求什么慰藉 又在逃避什么东西
From what does she seek solace? What does she not wish to see?
一个自以为是的傻瓜吗
A fool embarrassing himself?
哦 有了
Oh, yes.
愚者
The Fool.
某人误入歧途 身陷自己也不了解的事件
Someone has been led astray, involved in something without their knowledge.
还不错 但是
Not bad, but
你还不足以让我信服
you have to make me believe you.
再拿点诚意出来吧
I have to see it in your eyes.
很好 我还能做得更好
Right. I can do better.
圣杯之二 象征坚韧的纽带
The Two of Cups, a powerful bond.
联系谁呢 也许是姐姐和弟弟吧
But between whom? A brother and sister perhaps?
我能看到一个名字 没错 就是
And I see a name. Yes, it's…
芮内
…Rene.
你想要怎样
What do you want?
一张恶魔
The Devil.
你到底在玩什么花样
Why are we playing this game?
你从哪里得来的
Where did you get this?
我从拍卖行一个女人那里偷来的
I stole it from a woman in an auction room,
但我相信它是寄给你的
but I believe it was intended for you.
亲爱的西姆
记住我的脸 因为你再也见不到它了
只有付出这样的代价
才能改变历史的进程
我终于找到我人生的意义
找到我人生的意义
"Found my purpose in life."
所以 我一直想问的问题是
So the question I've been holding is,
芮内人生的意义是什么
what purpose is Rene fulfilling?
时间到了
Time is up.
我还有别的客人
I have other clients.
尽管我猜你可能还没发现我右肩上方的
Though you may not have detected the wisp of astrakhan fur…
木钉上挂着一缕俄国羊毛
…snagged on a nail over my left shoulder…
但是你一定不会没有闻到
…you couldn't have failed to notice the overpowering aroma…
腌鲱鱼和伏特加的味道
…of herring pickled in vodka…
以及那股浓重刺鼻的体味
…in tandem with a truly unfortunate body odor.
我们头顶的房梁上躲着个人
There's a man concealed in the rafters above us.
哥萨克人 他们的运动能力举世闻名
A Cossack, renowned for their infeasible acrobatic abilities…
一样出名的还有他们夜间的刺杀活动
…and are notorious for moonlighting as assassins.
因此可以肯定你的下一个客人
So it's safe to presume that your next client
是来杀你的
is here to kill you.
还想算什么吗 没了吗
Anything else? No?
首先 掏翻鸟窝
First, pillage the nest.
剪掉翅膀
Clip wings.
然后 猛击鸟嘴
Now blunt his beak.
敲碎鸟蛋
Crack eggs.
混匀 适量加盐
Scramble. Pinch of salt.
胡椒少许
Touch of pepper.
把煎蛋翻一面
Flip the omelet.
再加上必要的调味料
Additional seasoning required.
早饭做好了
Breakfast is served.
跟我来 你可不能死 快
Come with me. I need you alive. Now.
这一招你没算到吧
Didn't see that in the cards, did you?
冷静点 伙计们
Coming down, folks, coming down.
看样子我们又能再赌上一局了
Looks like we've got ourselves our next cockfight.
五 四 三 二 一
Five, four, three, two, one…
放开他
…let him go!
追上去
Get up there!
都是我的
AII mine?
等一下
Now, wait a minute.
你说得对 他确实很臭
You're right. He did stink.
嘿 你再跑啊
Hey, you can run…
你在哪里
Where's you?
刚打了一架
Just had a fight.
没错
Yes.
- 你去哪儿了？- 很高兴见到…
- Where were you? - I'm glad to see…
看到你这个伴郎如此尽责我非常欣慰
…you're taking your best-man duties so seriously.
我寡不敌众
I was on my own!
我的钱都要不回来了
Not gonna get my monies!
她还咬我的腿
She was biting my leg.
我让卡罗瑟去给你们的汽车加点燃料
I'II have Carruthers put some fuel into that motor carriage of yours.
你们还有婚礼要参加
You do have a wedding to attend.
我来开车
Oh, I'II drive.
嘀嘀
Ho-honk. Ha-ha-ha.
我们再喝一杯嘛
Let's have another drink.
不 我想你已经喝得够多了
No, no, I think you've had quite enough.
我也来这里参加过婚礼
I've been to a wedding here before.
还有葬礼
Funeral too.
教授想见见你
The professor wants to meet.
考虑到最近发生的事情 他早该来找我了
I'd expected to hear from him sooner, in light of recent events.
他想知道今天下午你可否去大学跑一趟
He was wondering if it'd be convenient for you to come by the college this afternoon.
他的课四点结束
His lecture concludes at 4.
非常乐意
Looking forward.
让一让 兄弟
One side, chummy.
《渔夫之歌》 舒伯特 一八二六年
"Fischerweise, " Schubert, 1826.
放弃你那些愚蠢的伎俩
"Give up your foolish trickery."
这条鱼不受欺骗
"This fish you cannot cheat."
希望我没打扰你们
I hope I'm not intruding.
稍等片刻
Excuse me.
马修 把这些带去交给威廉姆斯先生
Matthew, take these up to Mr. Williams.
让他记得带上我的白色领带和燕尾服
And make sure he packs my white tie and tails.
我知道了 教授
I'II take care of it, professor.
谢谢
Thank you.
真的很抱歉 我就要开始巡回演讲了
I do apologize.I'm off on a blasted lecture tour.
你想喝茶还是咖啡
Would you care for some tea or coffee?
都不用
Neither.
那来点烈性饮料吧
Something stronger, perhaps?
不了 但是能否麻烦您给我签个名
No, but might I trouble you for an inscription?
（小行星动力学及课堂笔记 詹姆斯·莫里亚蒂教授 著）
我听说那位好大夫今天结婚了
I read that the good doctor was to be married today.
婚礼怎么样
How was the service?
圆满完成
Definitive.
他不再是我的侦查伙伴 没有半点干系
He'll no longer be party to my investigations. He's out of the equation.
这一点相信你一定会充分考虑的
I trust you'll take this into consideration.
（室内园艺的艺术）
那你有没有为我考虑呢
And what considerations will you grant me?
你认真看过这本书吗
Have you actually read the book?
我觉得很有说服力
I found it compelling…
尽管我主要的兴趣还是你最近的工作
…though I'm primarily interested in your more recent endeavors.
非常感谢你的赞美
I take that as a compliment.
我对你的才华也相当敬佩
I have the utmost regard for your talents.
我很荣幸终于能和你
It's a pleasure to finally meet you…
正式见面了
…officially.
不知你对笔迹学有没有研究
Are you familiar with the study of graphology?
不 我没有太在意这个方面
I've never given it any serious thought, no.
对书写笔迹的心理分析
The psychological analysis of handwriting.
从你上半部分的Ｐ和Ｊ和Ｍ
The upward strokes on the P, the J,
可以看出智慧高人一等
and the M indicate a genius-level intellect.
而下半部分的华丽笔法则说明
While the flourishes on the lower zone…
你富于创造又非常严谨的天性
…denote a highly creative yet meticulous nature.
但如果把字体倾斜 和运笔的力度结合起来
But if one observes the overall slant and the pressure of the writing…
就可以看出你这个人极度自恋
…there's a suggestion of acute narcissism,
完全丧失同情心
a complete lack of empathy…
并且严重倾向于
…and a pronounced inclination toward…
错
No.
道德沦丧
…moral insanity.
关于你之前提到的
In answer to your previous request
华生大夫与此事无关的说法
regarding Dr. Watson not being involved…
我的回答是 错
…the answer is no.
天体运动的法则告诉我们
The laws of celestial mechanics dictate
当两个物体碰撞时
that when two objects collide…
总会有些影响
…there is always damage
波及到周边
of a collateral nature.
举例来说
Exempli gratia.
两位男士 意见不合势同水火
Two gentlemen find themselves at cross-purposes.
年轻的女士 挣扎于两人之间
A young woman torn between them.
这压力令她难以承受
The strain proves too much for her,
她突然之间病倒
and she suddenly falls ill…
结果以悲剧收场
…with tragic consequences.
一种罕见的结核病例
A rare form of tuberculosis.
短短数秒就夺去了她的生命
She succumbed in a matter of seconds.
现在
Now…
你确定要下这局棋吗
…are you sure you want to play this game?
恐怕你会输
I'm afraid you'd lose.
不用担心 如果你想置我于死地
Rest assured, if you attempt to bring destruction down upon me…
我也不会心慈手软
…I shall do the same to you.
我对你的敬重 福尔摩斯先生
My respect for you, Mr. Holmes,
是你活到现在的唯一原因
is the only reason you're still alive.
你的好话说了不少
You've paid me several compliments.
我也有一言相告
Let me pay you one in return…
如果我想要的结果可以达到的话
…when I say that if I were assured of the former eventuality…
我愿意付出任何代价
…I would cheerfully accept the latter.
我一定会向那对新人致以诚挚的问候
I'II be sure to send my regards to the happy couple.
改日再聚吧
Another time, then.
准备发车去布莱顿
AII aboard for Brighton!
准备发车
AII aboard!
哪个车厢来着
Which coach are we?
我们应该就在这儿
We should be just here.
一等车厢
First class.
去布莱顿的列车即将发车
AII aboard for Brighton! AII aboard!
快上车 华生大夫 你的妻子需要你
Hurry up, Dr. Watson, your wife needs you.
这就来 华生太太
Coming, Mrs. Watson.
一等车厢和香槟
Ooh. First class, champagne.
你真会讨女孩子欢心 华生先生
You do know how to spoil a girl, Mr. Watson.
你可不是普通女孩子
You're not just any girl.
抱歉 夫人
I'm sorry, madam.
火车靠站期间不能使用洗手间
You can't use the lavatory while the train's in the station.
你可是华生太太
You're Mrs. Watson.
把瓶子给我
Give me that bottle.
这世界上除了你身边 我哪里也不想去
John, there is nowhere else in the world I would rather be.
我也只愿你一人陪在身边
There's no one I'd rather be with.
为什么你背后裤腰上会插着把枪呢
Why do you have a gun stuffed down the back of your trousers?
积习难改
Heh. Old habits.
请进
Ahem. Come in.
哦 好的 谢谢
Oh, yes, please.
我们没要这个
We didn't order that.
是我们附赠的 先生
With our compliments, sir.
谢谢 放那里吧
Thank you. Put it there.
打开车门 约翰
Open the door, John.
我想你可以出去了
I think it's time for you to leave.
坐下
Sit down.
我知道这不算是我最好的伪装
I agree it's not my best disguise,
但也只能凑合了
but I had to make do.
我的天哪
My God.
他们会回来的
They'll be back.
约翰 快关门
John, shut the door.
他们隔着门也会开枪的 亲爱的
Theyl only shoot through it.
他说得对
He's right, you know.
我的上帝呀
Oh, my God.
我很理解你
I understand.
是吗
Do you?
确实造成很多不便
Terribly inconvenient.
我们时间不多了
We don't have much time.
他们大概有多少人
How many are we expecting?
六七个吧
Half a dozen.
他们是谁
Who are they?
莫里亚蒂送你的结婚礼物
A wedding present from Moriarty.
顺便说一句 婚礼很棒
Lovely ceremony, by the way.
大家流下了喜悦的泪水
Many a tear shed in joy.
哦 约翰
Oh, John?
稍等片刻 亲爱的
Yeah, just a minute, darling.
你相信我吗
Do you trust me?
不
No.
既然如此我就得
Well, then I shall have to
有所表现才行
do something about that.
谁想下一个受死 你们这群畜生
Who's up to bat next, you bastards?
派点像样的人过来
Send out the fast bowler!
约翰 把门关上吧
John, do shut the door.
我别无选择
It had to be done.
她现在安全了
She's safe now.
你先听我说 我时机掌握得很好
In my own defense, I timed it perfectly.
你杀死了我妻子
Did you kill my wife?!
你居然杀死了我的新婚妻子
Did you just kill my new wife?!
当然没有
Of course not!
什么意思 你刚把她扔下火车怎么会没事
What do you mean? How do you know that when you just threw her off a train?
我说了 时机掌握得很好
I told you, I timed it perfectly.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?!
冷静点
Calm down.
回答我
Explain!
等我解释清楚我们也都死了
By the time I've explained, we'd both be dead!
抱歉夫人 火车靠站期间不能使用洗手间
I'm sorry, madam. You can't use the lavatory while the train's in the station.
（有人）
（磷 高度易燃）
（空闲）
这可不是巧合
That was no accident.
是我设计好的
It was by design.
现在
Now,
你是要听我详细说明
do you need me to elaborate…
还是我们先干正经事
…or can we just crack on?
快来
Come on!
别担心 老伙计
Don't worry, old boy,
她现在很安全 正和我哥哥在一起
she's as safe as houses.She's with my brother.
我正在度蜜月
I'm on my honeymoon!
你为什么引他们过来
Why did you lead them here?!
为什么要牵连我们
Why did you involve us?!
他们不是冲我来的而是冲你来的
They aren't here for me! They're here for you!
幸运的是
Fortunately…
我也来了
…so am I.
当心开门了
Now mind the door.
晚上好
Good evening.
我想你们会觉得二等车厢更加舒
I think you'll find that second class is more comfortable.
道路很畅通
The coast is clear.
快点去 跑起来
To the south, quick march.
陪我躺一会儿 华生
Lie down with me, Watson.
为什么
Why?
我执意如此
I insist.
我们躺下来干什么
What are we doing down here?
我们在等待 而我在抽烟
We are waiting. I am smoking.
耐心地等待
Patiently waiting.
等什么
For what?
让你反击的机会
Your window of opportunity.
不要失手
Make it count.
叫你不要失手
I said make it count.
我要给你创造几个机会才够呢
How many windows must I provide?
谁会想到去布莱顿度蜜月会如此凶险
Who'd have known that honeymooning in Brighton was such a dangerous notion?
你觉得是这个原因吗
Is that what this is about?
你自己也承认 你并不喜欢那地方
By your own admission, you've never enjoyed it there.
我就从来没去过布莱顿
I've never been to Brighton.
还是你现在吓得想不起来了
Or you're just too fragile to remember at present.
哦 闭嘴
Oh, shut up.
告诉我我妻子没事
Tell me my wife's safe.
这我不能同时办到
I can't do both.
肯定没事 说了 我的时机掌握得很好
I promise. As I said, I timed it perfectly.
到这儿来 夫人
Over here, madam!
我应该要祝你新婚快乐 华生太太
I believe congratulations are in order, Mrs. Watson.
我也叫福尔摩斯
I'm the other Holmes.
你是说有两个福尔摩斯吗
You mean there's two of you?
太棒了 今天晚上真是精彩极了
How marvelous. Could this evening get any better?
为什么我和玛丽会成为目标
Why were Mary and I targeted at all?
问得好
Excellent question.
这有两层原因
The answer is twofold.
他盯上我们都是因为你
He's after us because of you.
在这件事上恐怕你也有一半责任
I'm afraid you must bear half the responsibility.
你又来了
Here it comes.
要不是你和玛丽
Had you and Mary…
就知道会这样
So predictable.
这么迫不及待要结婚
…not been hell-bent on wedding,
这案子早就搞定了
we could've solved this case.
行行行 都怪我
Oh, it's my fault now.
我的意思是 你不得不承认
The argument could be made…
不 我不承认
No, it couldn't.
你婚礼办得实在不是时候
that your nuptials were poorly timed.
因此 我们的感情
Thus, our relationship…
什么感情
Relationship?
那好吧 我们的友谊还没有走到尽头
Very well, partnership.has not yet run its course.
我的朋友 如果你能帮我把这个案子了结
My dear fellow, if you could be bothered to see this through to the end…
我今后再也不来找你帮忙了
…I shall never again ask you to assist me.
最后一次 下不为例
Once more unto the breach.
就等你这句话
That's the spirit.
好 回到正题
Now, to the question.
案情复杂得让人欲罢不能
This is so deliciously complicated. You may be asking yourself…
你可能会问自己 一个犯罪首脑会想要从
…what does a criminal mastermind want
一个吉普赛占卜师那里得到什么
with a simple gypsy fortune teller?
是想要她的弟弟 我告诉你
It's her brother, I tell you.
等我们找到这个关键人物
When we find him, and we must…
你先找到我的行李
After you find my luggage.
去找吧
Go on.
等等
Wait.
我们这次要去哪儿
Where is it we're going?
巴黎 全世界最佳的蜜月胜地
Paris, the most sensible honeymoon destination of all.
为什么去巴黎
So why Paris?
有桃子
Peaches.
有一个以干果著称的吉普赛人营地
Outside the city at Montreuil…there's a Gypsy camp famous
桃子尤其出名
for its dried fruit, especially peaches.
在那个地方应该能找到
And there we shall find our fortune teller…
那个占卜师 然后把包还给她
…and return her bag.
（莫里亚蒂教授讲座）
这本书真是太棒了
谢谢您
您真是无与伦比
过奖了 谢谢
那么 我的票呢
And my ticket?
真是好书
谢谢
（唐璜 巴黎大剧院）
很不幸 你的票可能用不上了
Unfortunately, you won't be needing yours.
太可惜了 教授
That's a shame, professor.
我一直很想去看《唐璜》
I was looking forward to Don Giovanni.
谢谢
跟着迈哈德
Follow Meinhard.
谢谢 停
醒一醒 我们到了
Wake up, we're here.
做好准备 我们就要被调戏了
Brace yourself. We're about to be violated.
别这么杞人忧天
Don't be so cynical.
你好 我找 西姆萨
哦 知道 先生 我知道 她在呢
对 她在 在
太好了 太好了
他们拿走了我的行李
They're taking my luggage.
你不用担心 华生 她的包在我这儿
Laugh them away, Watson. I have her bag.
她的包在我这儿
她的包也拿走了
You had her bag.
现在外套也被拿走了
Now they have my coat.
西姆萨夫人在哪儿
Where is Madam Simza?
这就是西姆萨
This is Simza.
西姆是只鹅
Sim is a goose.
我是西姆 哈哈哈
I am Sim. Ha-ha-ha.
围巾不错 我喜欢
Nice scarf. I like.
此事有关他的弟弟
你饿不饿
You hungry?
饥饿难耐
Famished.
夫人 这道刺猬肉炖杂菜太美味了
Madam, this is a gloriou shedgehog goulash.
我不记得有吃过比这更好的
I can't remember ever having had better.
告诉我
Do tell me
你上次吃刺猬肉炖杂菜是什么时候
when was the last time you had a hedgehog goulash?
我说了 华生 我不记得了
I told you, Watson, I can't remember.
也许你只是在压抑
Perhaps you've repressed it.
我和你不一样 我从不压抑
That's where we differ. Unlike you, I repress nothing.
再正常不过了
Perfectly normal.
你怎么可以对一个邀请我们进她的帐篷
How dare you be rude to this woman who has invited us into her tent…
又给我们刺猬吃的女士如此无礼
…offered us her hedgehog?
作为把女士推下火车的人你有资格吗
Says the man who throws women from trains.
你们是什么人
Who are you two?
热心的公民
Concerned citizens.
为什么有人想要杀我
Why did someone try to kill me?
你弟弟结交了一个非常危险的人物
Your brother has become involved with a very dangerous man…
他确信芮内告诉了 你一些不该透露的事情
…who clearly believes that Rene has told you something you shouldn't know.
我什么都不知道
I don't know anything.
我找他找了一年多时间
I've been looking for him for over a year.
这就是我为什么会去伦敦
That was why I was in London.
那是他最后一次出现的地方
It's the last place anyone saw him.
显然你弟弟很爱你
It's clear that your brother loves you.
他绝对不会寄一些会对你不利的邮件
He'd never send you a message that would put you in harm's way.
因此透漏的信息都是由于疏忽大意
Any information, therefore, would be, by 456, unintentional.
他有寄给你其他东西吗
Has he sent you anything else?
只有几张画而已
Just a few drawings.
让我们来看看里面的奥妙
Let's just see what they have to tell us.
没选用一般的画纸
Unusual choice of paper.
比较厚 是印刷厂专用的
Thicker gauge, designed for a printing press.
这些纸的质地和信纸一样
And it's the same stock as the letter.
闻起来有霉味
They smell musty.
一定是存放在阴冷潮湿的地方
Must have been stored somewhere cold and damp.
那是什么 血迹吗
What's that? Blood?
红酒 一个靠近印刷厂的红酒酒窖
Wine. So a wine cellar located near a printing press.
范围缩小了
That should narrow it down.
他说他再也不会回去的
一个叫绿兔子的无政府组织有个酒窖
There's a wine cellar used by the anarchist group Lapin Vert.
芮内和他们的老大曾很有交情
Rene was close to their leader.
克劳德·哈瓦锡
Claude Ravache.
炸弹专家
A bomb maker.
我上个星期才见过他的作品
I sampled some of his work last week.
我曾是那组织的成员
I was a part of the movement.
芮内也是
So was Rene.
后来我们觉得它太极端了
Until it became too extreme for us.
哈瓦锡认识我
Ravache knows me.
如果我弟弟回去了 他会见我们的
If my brother's back there, he will see us.
我们这就去问他
We will send a message.
我去约哈瓦锡见面
好
无论如何 吉普赛人劝你喝酒你都别喝
Whatever you do, don't let these gypsies make you drink.
知道
Of course.
跳舞吗
You dance?
看在上帝的份上别跳 不然你就死定了
For God's sake, don't dance. It'll be the death of you.
你知道跳舞是什么下场吗
You know what happens when you dance.
早上好 华生太太
Oh, good morning, Mrs. Watson.
早饭吃过了吗
Have you had breakfast?
斯坦利做的辣烤羊腰棒极了
Stanley here does a wonderful deviled kidney.
卡罗瑟
Carruthers?
早安 先生
Morning, sir.
有华生太太的电报
Telegram for Mrs. Watson.
我一点也看不懂
It just doesn't make any sense.
乐意效劳
Allow me.
有了
Oh, yes.
我最厌恶的玛丽
"My most loathed Mary,
我一点也不爱你 再也不想见你了
I do not love you. I never wish to see you again.
离开你的每一秒钟都是祝福
Every moment I count away from you is a blessing."
别担心
Fret not.
这是双重密码 亲爱的
It's a double encryption, my dear…
我和歇利小时候就开始用了
…that Sherly and I have used since we were boys.
如果信息的第一个字母是个辅音
If the first letter of the message is a consonant…
那信息的真实含义就和表述相反
…then what follows is the mirrored truth.
好吧
I see.
斯坦利
Stanley!
我说 尽管我们相处的时间非常短
You know, although our time together has been but a brief interlude…
但我开始理解为什么 有着某些特点的男性
…I'm beginning to understand how a man of particular disposition…
在某些特殊情况下 或许是极端情况下
…under certain circumstances, extreme ones perhaps…
会变得喜欢身边有一个
…might grow to enjoy the company of…
像你这样性别的人
…a person of your gender. Hmm.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
你过奖了
Most charming.
不好意思 谢谢
May… Terribly sorry. Thank you.
你要去哪里啊 斯坦利
Where are you going, Stanley?
（七蛙餐厅）
你们到了 下车吧
跟我来
进来进来
还躲在地下室吗
Still hiding in basements?
最近这阵子不方便出去
能见到你我很高兴
我不是来看你的
I'm not here to see you.
来吧
Yeah.
我很想将这一时刻…
与你的英国朋友分享
With your English friends.
一七八九年 很有意义的年份
1789, a seminal vintage.
那是我们大革命的一年
The year of our glorious revolution.
他在这儿吗
Is he here?
自由战胜暴政的一年
When freedom triumphed over tyranny.
我弟弟在吗
Is my brother here?
我很久没见过他了
I haven't seen him for a long time.
你在撒谎
You're lying.
请坐
Sit, please.
芮内寄来的信纸和这儿的一样
A letter was received from Rene using this same paper.
那当然 他去哪里都随身携带
Of course. He took it with him wherever he went.
他没骗你 芮内不在这儿
He's telling the truth. Rene isn't here.
他的任务是去协助一个
He was given another assignment by an…
一个不具名的赞助人
An anonymous benefactor.
另一个英国人
Another Englishman…
他有钱 有权 支持我们的事业
…with money, power, who supported our cause.
而现在
And now…
我们全都要听他的
…he dictates our every move…
却要我为他的恐怖袭击负责
…demanding I take responsibility for his acts of terror.
我和恶魔定了契约
I made a deal with the devil.
但过了今晚
But after tonight, ahem…
一切就结束了
…it will be over.
我的任务快完成了
My job is almost done.
他又让你放了个炸弹 对不对
He's had you plant another bomb, hasn't he?
克劳德 告诉他们
Claude, please.
他们俩可以帮助你
These men can help you.
我也希望他们可以
I wish they could.
知道吗 先生们
You see, gentlemen…
我老婆和孩子在他手上
…he has my wife and children.
如果你告诉我炸弹在哪里
If you tell us where the bomb is…
我会想办法救你的家人
…I'II find a way to help your family.
这事不用你操心了
That's already taken care of.
我们都说好了
We have a deal.
我和他
He and I.
不留后患
No loose ends.
要保证我家人安全我只有一个选择
There's only one thing I can do to keep my family safe.
你们只剩不到十分钟时间了
You have less than 10 minutes.
不要
Don't!
发生什么了 走 去看看 快
那手枪对他没用 不如你拿来掩护楼梯
He has no further need of that pistol. Why don't you take it and cover the stairs?
快去看看 快
这个地方就一个出口
There's only one way out of this place.
你说得对
Right you are.
别具匠心
Ah. Ingenious.
就是这个 我们快走吧
That's the one. Quickly as we can.
你知道该如何处理那个沙袋 华生
You know what to do with that sandbag, Watson.
快点
Quick now.
快下去看看
大夫 请确认一下那个拉杆
Doctor, could you secure that lever?
你早该告诉我
You could have told me.
哈瓦锡很坚强
Ravache was strong.
他为自由而生 不会轻易自杀的
He lived for liberty.He would never take his own life.
冷静一点
Calm yourself.
我弟弟 他很脆弱
My brother, he's weak.
西姆 你先深吸一口气
Sim, I need you to take a deep breath…
然后跟着我们
…and follow us.
快去大剧院
To the opera.
（商业峰会 迈哈德下榻凯旋门大酒店）
（凯旋门大酒店）
我想错了
I was mistaken.
什么
What?
我犯了个错误
I made a mistake.
尽管政治上我们有分歧
商业让我们团结
他选在这个位置
He took the shot from here.
还用了三脚架和枪托
Using a tripod and a shooting stick.
然后意识到还有个更好的位置
And realized there was a better position.
这道浅痕说明他把三脚架拖到了这里
There's a faint scrape where he dragged his tripod and set it up here.
大概六百码吧
Six hundred yards?
或者六百五十码
Or 650?
更别提还有时速七 八英里的风
Not to mention a seven- or eight-mile-an-hour wind.
他还得要个风速计
He would've needed a wind gauge.
就放在这里
Which he placed here.
还在这里放了根香烟
And put a cigarette down here.
这么远能打中吗
Can anyone shoot that far?
这种人整个欧洲不过五六个
Not more than half a dozen men in all of Europe.
这些人有几个参加过阿富汗战争
How many of those men served in Afghanistan?
怎么
Why?
赫什朋加泰克尔的混合烟草
Hirschsprung with a touch of Tekel.
肯定是卷烟的时候掉下来的
Must have fallen out when he was rolling up.
你们军队都是抽这种的吧
Wasn't that the blend you all smoked?
我听说过某个上校的事
Didn't I read something about a colonel?
塞巴斯汀·莫兰
Sebastian Moran.
英国陆军的头号神枪手
Best marksman in the British army.
行为不检革除军籍
Dishonorable discharge.
现在可能当职业杀手了
He's likely now a gun for hire.
这是我遇到的第二个他的受害者
This is the second victim of his that I've encountered.
还有什么能更好地掩盖谋杀
What better way to conceal a killing?
没人会在爆炸现场去找弹孔
No one looks for a bullet hole in a bomb blast.
迟到了二十分钟
He's 20 minutes late.
肯定快到了
He must come soon.
我身上可没证件
I don't have any papers.
我又是个外国人
And I am a foreigner.
这种局面就是莫里亚蒂最想要的
This climate is exactly what Moriarty wants.
香草煎蛋 很好吃
Ahem. The omelet fines herbes was divine…
但这儿的茶简直太次了
…but they spared every expense on the tea.
现在我们是继续抱怨还是先理清思路
Now shall we compare moods, or consider what we know?
昨天的爆炸显然想让人以为是
Last night's bombing was clearly meant…
德国对斯特拉斯堡事件的报复
…to look like Germany's retaliation for Strasbourg.
但真正目的是 掩饰一起针对个人的谋杀案
However, the bomb was also meant to conceal the murder of just one man.
被枪杀的男人就是阿尔弗雷德·迈哈德
The man killed by the gunshot was none other than Alfred Meinhard.
他是军火商 重型军火
He makes guns. Big guns.
几天前某不明投资人 买了他公司大量股票
Only days ago, a large share of his company was bought by an unknown investor.
莫里亚蒂
Moriarty.
线索提示了一个方向
The clues point in one direction,
但为了避免重蹈昨晚的覆辙
but to avoid repeating last night's debacle…
我有必要收集够充分的证据
…I was obliged to collect more sufficient data, hence my tardiness.
所以我来迟了
（欧洲和平进程受挫）
（凯旋门大酒店发生爆炸）
离开车还有四十分钟 先生
Train departs in 40 minutes, sir.
先生 你的外套 谢谢
你拿行李就行了
Just the bags.
但是
But…
我还有时间来满足一下我的兴趣爱好吧
We have enough time for me to indulge my little habit.
是的
Yes.
他的兴趣爱好就是去喂那些城里的鸽子
His habit of feeding that urban species, the feral pigeon.
巴黎有七个主干线火车站
So there are seven mainline railway stations in Paris.
但能让他花个十分钟跑去杜乐丽花园
But taking 10 minutes to get to the Jardin des Tuileries…
去找那群长着翅膀的寄生虫
…where the largest concentration of the winged vermin may be found…
就只有一种可能 巴黎北站
…reduces there to one, the Gare du Nord…
他正好可以赶上 十一点零四分开往柏林的火车
…where he will be just in time to catch the 11:04 train to Berlin.
这趟车沿路会停几站 其中就有
It makes several stops along the way, one of which is…
海尔布隆
Heilbronn.
正是我们要去的地方
Exactly where we must go.
迈哈德的工厂 就在那里
Where Meinhard's factory is.
现在是莫里亚蒂的工厂了
It's Moriarty's factory now.
很遗憾 由于爆炸
Unfortunately, due to the bombing…
法德两国间的通道关闭了
…the crossing between France and Germany is to be closed.
本案的追查到此结束 除非我们碰巧遇到
I'm afraid our pursuit is over unless we can happen upon a comrade…
一位很熟悉边境地形的同伴
…who knows their way around borders.
太英国了
Too English.
不过你确实很像吉普赛人
However, you do make a fantastic gypsy.
浑身散发着吉普赛的味道
Certainly smell like a fantastic gypsy.
你没必要这么损
Now, now, no need to be demeaning.
这是你的漂亮围巾
It is a nice scarf.
不 太英国了 比较适合你
No, no, too English. It'll suit you more.
谢谢
黑马是你的 灰马是我的
Black one is yours. Gray one is mine.
这匹马是你的
And this is for you.
对了
Right.
马车呢
Where are the wagons?
马车太慢了 你不会骑吗
The wagon is too slow.Can't you ride?
不是他不会骑马
It's not that he can't ride.
你怎么解释的
How is it you put it, Holmes?
这种动物两头都危险 中间又麻烦
They're dangerous at both ends and crafty in the middle.
我不想要一个有自我意识的东西
Why would I want anything with a mind
在我的两腿间上下耸动
of its own bobbing about between my legs?
那我就要一辆自行车吧 非常感谢
Then I shall require a bicycle, thank you very much.
都一八九一年了 就该租一个热气球
It's 1891. Could've chartered a balloon.
有没有简单点的办法
How can we make this more manageable?
火烧眉毛了吗
Where's the fire?
德国又不会逃走的
It's not as if Germany is going somewhere.
还有另一条路
We know another way.
坚持不懈才会胜利
Slow and steady wins the race.
快来
Come on!
我们从卸货码头溜进去
We slip in through the loading bay,
找到他的把柄
find out what he's doing…
然后溜出来
…and we get out.
溜出来有点难度
Getting out might be tricky.
我们会来接应你们
We will get you out.
如果我弟弟在里面 带他活着出来
If my brother's in there, get him out alive.
你开心吗
Are you happy?
什么
What?
在此时此刻
At this moment…
你是不是和去布莱顿度蜜月一样开心
…are you as happy as you would be on your honeymoon in Brighton?
我根本懒得去回答这个问题
I'm not going to grace that question with an answer.
你开心吗
Are you happy?
我认为我们来这儿是有其他原因的
I think we're here for another reason.
好吧
Okay.
让我们开始做
Shall we get on…
这并不难回答
Simple question.
我们是去办正经事
Will we do something?
还是在这里等他们转回来
Or wait for them to come back round?
现在几点
What time is it?
- 三点十五分 - 在那…
- Three-fifteen. - Over there…
在这个设施的居住区里应该有个电报室
…in the residential part of the complex should be a telegraph office.
把这个发给迈克罗夫特 整点时回这里来
Send this to Mycroft. Be back here on the hour.
（迈哈德邮政与电报局）
（电报局）
（德国）
（斯德哥尔摩 赫尔辛基 莫斯科）
（荷兰）
（海尔布隆）
当工业与武器联姻 这就是它们的产物
That's what you get, Mr. Holmes, when industry marries arms.
把你的枪放下
Now put your gun down.
它已经过时了
It's a bit old-fashioned.
你应该搞一把这种枪
What you need is one of these.
去拿吧
Go on.
挑一把
Pick one.
机关手枪
Machine pistol,
自动连发
self-repeating.
使用了七点六三口径的子弹
Takes 7.63 caliber rounds…
装在这里面
…in one of these.
荷载十发子弹的盒式弹匣
A 10-shot box magazine.
装填十分方便
Easy enough to load.
我估计要拉一下枪栓才能让子弹上膛
I'd imagine one would have to retract the bolt to engage the first round.
比说得还简单
Easier done than said.
把他送去手术室
Take him to the surgery.
我去把医生找来
I'II find the doctor.
如果方便的话请来一趟
"Come at once if convenient.
如果不方便 也请来一趟
If inconvenient, come all the same."
这是杜松子酒
This is schnapps.
你在这里发了个电报
A telegram was sent from here.
这不是杜松子酒 是阿夸维特
This isn't schnapps, it's aquavit,
是从土豆泥里蒸馏出来的
distilled from potato mash.
经常有人会弄错 不过还是谢谢了
A common misconception. Thank you, by the way.
电报发给谁了
Who was it sent to?
我对你的罪行恐惧之至 就如同
My horror at your crimes is matched only…
我对你实施罪行时的技巧钦佩至极
…by my admiration at the skill it took to achieve them.
电报发给谁了
Who was it sent to?
你利用无政府主义者和他们的炸弹
You used the anarchists and their bombs to create a crisis in Europe…
在欧洲各国间制造了一个又一个危机
…nation against nation.
你用多个假名收买算计甚至
Under various pseudonyms, you bought, schemed, or murdered your way…
通过谋杀来渗透各行各业
…into numerous industries,
却不留下与你有关的蛛丝马迹
assuring that none of it could be traced to you.
棉花 鸦片 钢铁 以及军火和化学武器
Cotton, opium, steel, now arms and chemical weaponry.
所有东西一周之内就能运到欧洲各地
All to be shipped across Europe in less than a week.
从子弹到绷带一应俱全
Everything from bullets to bandages.
既然已掌握了供给
Now that you own the supply,
你就打算创造需求了
you intend to create the demand.
一场世界大战
A world war.
你很熟悉舒伯特的作品
You are familiar with Schubert's work.
站住 别动
《鳟鱼》 可能是我的最爱
The Trout is perhaps my favorite.
快跪下
一个渔夫急于抓住一条狡猾的鱼
A fisherman grows weary of trying to catch an elusive fish.
快让开 快让开
Out the way, out the way.
所以他搅浑河水
So he muddies the water.
我警告你哦
I'm warning you.
迷惑了那条鱼
Confuses the fish.
别耍花招
警告过你的
You were warned.
等它发现自己进入陷阱的时候已经太迟
It doesn't realize until too late that it has swum into a trap.
∮ 明亮的小溪里 有一条鳟鱼 ∮
∮ 它纵情欢乐 穿梭如箭 ∮
∮ 我站在小溪旁 静静地观望 ∮
∮ 在清澈的溪水里 它游得多欢畅 ∮
我们再试一次 好吗
Let's try this again, shall we?
那封电报你发给谁了
To whom did you send the telegram?
给我的
To my…
给我的哥哥迈克罗夫特
To my brother Mycroft.
你这是在玩什么
What are you playing at?
太不公平了
That's not fair.
我最后还有一个问题要问你
I've just got one more question for you.
我们两个谁是渔夫
Which one of us is the fisherman…
谁是鳟鱼
…and which the trout?
福尔摩斯
Holmes?
不着急 慢慢找
Take your time. Take your time.
见到你总是很高兴 华生
Always good to see you, Watson.
你是想找死吗
What were you thinking?
等等
Wait.
等什么
Wait?
告诉你吧 我想我抓到他了
Well, if you must know, I was thinking I had him right where I wanted him.
就在我想抓他的地方
好了 继续吧
Right. Crack on, then.
教授
Professor.
我没事 我没事
I'm all right, I'm all right.
别浪费时间来帮我
Don't waste time attending to me.
还愣着干什么
快追 追
我要抓住他们
I'II find them.
转身倒数 三 二 一
Turn in three, two, one.
快点过来
Come on, hurry up!
走
Go!
快 快
找到我弟弟了吗
Did you see my brother?
没有 但他肯定来过这里
No, but I'm certain he's been here.
我们该往哪儿走
Where are we going?
去围墙那里
Over that wall.
福尔摩斯 你怎么知道我找得到你
How did you know I'd find you?
你没在找我 你是在用塔楼砸我
You didn't find me.You collapsed a building on me.
动作快点 赶快
谁他妈让你们把墙给轰了
马在哪里
Where are the horses?
在后面
They're behind.
我们需要它们
We need them.
你想回去吗
You wanna go back?
退路在哪里
What's our way out?
退路在那里
That's our way out.
你们这群蠢货
谁他妈让你们把墙给轰了
赶快给我追 快点
别让他们跑了 快给我追
快 快点 追
如果让他们跑了
你们就等死吧
迫击炮手准备
准备开火 对准目标
轮到小汉塞尔上场了
开火
Fire!
把手举起来
快 快
Go! Go!
快上去
Come on!
马可 马可
Marko! Marko!
他没有呼吸了
He's not breathing.
抱住他的头
Cradle his head.
把脚抬起来
Raise his legs.
你千万别给我死了
Bloody well not gonna die on me.
我不会对你手下留情的
I'm not gonna make this easy on you.
呼吸
Come on.
我知道你听得见的 自私的畜生
I know you can hear me, you selfish bastard.
呼吸啊
Come on!
我知道你听得见的 自私的畜生
I know you can hear me, you bastard.
他的结婚礼物
His wedding gift.
噩梦啊
Terrible dream.
你 玛丽 格莱斯顿和我在餐厅吃饭
You, Mary, Gladstone and I were in a restaurant.
那只矮脚马也在那里
That satanic pony was there as well,
蹄子上拿了把大叉子想要吃了我
a massive fork in his hoof…and he turned on me!
你打了什么药
What have you administered?
你的结婚礼物
Your wedding present.
谁在我胸口上跳过舞
Who's been dancing on my chest?!
我
Me.
为什么我脚踝那么痒
Why is my ankle so itchy?
因为有一大块的碎木片插在它上面
You have a large piece of wood sticking out of it.
我的天哪 嘿 塔马斯
Good Lord. You, Tamas.
我有件重要的事情要和你说
I have an important job to discuss with you.
记得等会儿提醒我
Remind me of it later.
坐下 把这个喝了
Sit down. Drink this.
我要在出现败血症前把它取出来
I need to get that out before it turns septic.
你是不是骂我自私的畜生
Did you call me "selfish bastard"?
有可能
Probably.
还是别拔了 别拔了
Just leave it in. Leave it…
你这家伙简直是
You are a…Oh, you are some sort of…
别惹我
Be nice.
我很遗憾你没去成布莱顿
I'm sorry you didn't get to Brighton.
我也是
Me too.
我们该回家了
I think we should go home.
我同意
I concur.
我们回家吧
We're going home.
顺路去趟瑞士
Via Switzerland.
想挑起战争的最佳地点
What better place to start a war
就是和平峰会
than a peace summit?
我们正好去看我哥哥 他一定很想你
We'll drop in and see my brother. I'm sure he's missed you. Hm?
我还是不理解你为何不取消这次峰会
I don't understand why you don't cancel the summit.
事实是无论我们怎么想它都会召开
Fact is it's gonna happen whether we like it or not.
所有政要都到齐了
Everyone has already arrived.
这些先生们或许在谈和平
Although these gentlemen may be talking peace…
相信我 他们都做好了战争的准备
…believe me, they're readying their armies at home.
现在取消峰会就等于宣告战争
To cancel the summit now would be tantamount to war.
那封电报还不够清楚吗
The telegram, wasn't it clear?
我们增加了一倍的警力 先生
We have doubled the security, sir.
双倍的警力 真叫人安心
Oh, doubled security. That's comforting.
你还不明白现在的情况有多微妙
You don't understand the delicacy of the situation.
我把电报交给了我的上级 但他们就是
I passed the telegram on to my superiors.
一开始把莫里亚蒂拉来当和平顾问的人
But they brought Moriarty in to advise on the peace process in the first place.
他现在的身份很有优势
He has positioned himself brilliantly.
他是我国最重要的智囊 又是现任首相的
He's one of our foremost intellectuals, a personal friend…
现任首相的私交好友 这个我们都知道
Of the prime minister. Yes, we all know that.
我相信你 但你的证据在哪里
I believe you, but where's your evidence?
他厉害到从不留下证据
He's too good to leave evidence.
办事滴水不漏
He doesn't leave loose ends.
他还活着
Oh, he's alive.
歇利 快放下
Sherly, put that down.
这个装置有什么用 给我好吗
What is this contraption? May I have it?
吸了以后真有点兴奋
The effect is most invigorating.
那是我私人专用的氧气储备 你不要乱碰
That's my private and personal supply of oxygen, and you're not to touch it.
这么讨论下去没有意义
This argument is getting us nowhere.
我准备了一些文件让你们可以参加舞会
I've arranged for documents to be prepared which allow you into the ball.
卡罗瑟
Carruthers.
斯坦利 斯坦利
Stanley, Stanley.
你一点都没有变 这是我最爱的甜辣酱吗
You haven't aged a day. Is that my favorite chutney?
问题是 我们还没弄清楚他的计划
Fact is, we don't really know what he's planning.
不会再用炸弹了
It won't be another bomb.
这次不会用炸弹的
No, it wouldn't be.
那样做没有意义
It doesn't make sense.
袭击所有国家 只会令他们团结
Why would he attack all the nations only to unite them?
应该会有暗杀
It'l be an assassination.
被一个孤胆枪手近身刺杀
By a lone gunman at close range.
芮内
Rene.
很不幸 是他
Unfortunately, yes.
你都知道
You knew.
我之前只是怀疑
I had my suspicions.
但在看过出席名单后我就确定了
But having seen who would be attending, I'm now certain.
现在起码知道该防着谁了
Well, at least we know who to look out for.
芮内就是证据
Rene will be the evidence.
如果能找到他 阻止他
If we can find him and stop him,
我们可能不止救了他的命
we will perhaps not only save his life…
还避免了西方文明的崩溃
…but prevent the collapse of Western civilization.
别有压力
No pressure.
欢迎 大使先生
Welcome, ambassador.
詹姆斯·莫里亚蒂教授
Professor James Moriarty.
既然大家都到了 我就告诉你们
Now we're all present…I can tell you
本次的主角是德国总理和他的大使
that the targets are the German chancellor and his ambassador…
还有法国首相和他的手下
…the French prime minister and his man.
其他国家实际上是来
And the other nations are really working out
判断一旦开战应该站在哪一边
which side to take should hostilities erupt.
那是迈克尔王子 沙皇的表亲 和俄国大使
Prince Michael, a cousin of the czar, and the Russian ambassador.
大公爵卡尔·路威格和奥匈帝国大使
The Archduke Karl Ludwig and the Austro-Hungarian ambassador.
罗马尼亚首相和他的大使
The Romanian Prime Minister and his ambassador.
当然 还有我们的首相和英国大使
And of course our prime minister and the British ambassador.
他应该会选一个所有政要到齐的时候
Hel choose a moment when the dignitaries are assembled,
最好是站着不动
preferably standing still.
有没有安排拍集体照
Is there to be an official photograph?
当然 有的
Indeed, yes.
还有三十八分钟
In 38 minutes.
既然如此 我们不如跳个舞
In which case, we might as well dance.
我从来没跳过这个
I've never done this before.
跟我跳就行了
Just follow my lead.
你看到了什么
What do you see?
一切
Everything.
这就是我的不幸
That is my curse.
可你没看到你要找的
But you don't see what you're looking for.
以为你不会请我了
I thought you'd never ask.
在我肩膀后面
Over my shoulder.
年轻人 穿德国制服 带仪式佩剑
Young man, German uniform, ceremonial sword.
看到了
Got him.
有什么专业意见
Professional opinion?
伤痕
Trauma.
受过重创
Major injury.
但整形手术很成功
But excellent repair work.
是霍芬斯塔大夫
Dr. Hoffmanstahl.
你说过他是医学创新的开拓者
You did say he was at the forefront of a medical innovation.
我们其实已经见过他的杰作了
We've already seen an example of his skills.
那两个人不是双胞胎
Those twins weren't twins.
在海尔布隆时我产生了怀疑
My suspicions were aroused in Heilbronn…
一个中枪倒地另一个却不帮忙
…when one failed to go to the aid of the other.
我还注意到他耳后 有块隐蔽却独特的皱褶
I also noticed the discreet but unmistakable puckering behind the ear…
那里的皮肤被拉过
…where his skin had been drawn back. I should've realized then…
我当时就该意识到他们是手术的实验品
…that they were a surgical experiment.
试验能不能让一个人长得就像另一个人
To see if it is possible to make one man look like another.
他的脸已经不是他自己的了
His face is no longer his own.
确保世界大战发生的 最好办法就是让刺客
What better way to guarantee his world war than to make the assassin…
成为一名大使
One of the ambassadors.
这就把范围缩小为六人中的一个
That narrows down the possibility to one of six.
你和西姆定能找出她弟弟 我毫不怀疑
You and Sim shall find her brother.Of this I have no doubt.
福尔摩斯
Holmes.
你知道我的计划
You know my methods.
我也知道你要去哪里
And I know where youl be.
这是我可以想到的最好的解决办法
No possible solution could be more congenial to me than this.
对了 你跳舞是谁教的
By the way, who taught you how to dance?
你教的
You did.
我教得还不错
Well, I've done a fine job.
小心点
Be careful.
我们开始吧
Shall we go to work?
女士们先生们 请集合拍照
Ladies and gentlemen, please, gather for the portrait.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
没有打扰你吧
Is this a bad time?
来得正好
Never better.
能把钟拿来吗
Would you bring that clock?
终于有机会下棋了
We get to play that game after all.
披上这个
Here we are.
我可不希望你感冒
Don't want you to catch a cold.
下五分钟快棋
A five-minute game?
只要你没问题就行
If you think you can manage it.
我们每人有两个象
We both have two bishops.
我人虽然不在房间里 但我的战术还在
I may be absent from the room, but my methods are not.
你该不会指望华生大夫吧
You can't mean Dr. Watson, surely.
这样不太公平
That doesn't seem fair.
手术会留下伤疤
Right. The surgery will have left scars.
只有四个人的鬓脚能够藏得住
Only four of them have the hairline to hide them.
被你用芮内掉包的大使 他还活着吗
The ambassador that you replaced with Rene, is he still alive?
要我提示你下一步棋怎么走吗
Would you like me to recommend your next move?
都和我弟弟差不多高.体形也一样.但是
They're all my brother's height, right build…
他们的眼睛
…but their eyes.
颜色不对 芮内是蓝眼睛
Their eyes are wrong. Rene has blue eyes.
可能是带了能变色的玻璃镜片
He could be wearing glass lenses to change the color.
如果这样 眼睛应该会疼
In which case, his eyes will be hurting.
芮内是左撇子
Rene is left-handed.
也许杀手会采取措施来避免暴露身份
Perhaps the assassin will take measures…to ensure he doesn't give himself away.
就像赌徒掩饰手上的牌
Like a gambler concealing a tell.
我感觉 可能是他
I think it might be him.
你感觉
You think?
你的钟还在走
Your clock is ticking.
你可得肯定
You have to be sure.
我提醒你 这可是快棋
May I remind you, this is blitz chess.
一次计算失误就会全盘皆输
A single miscalculation will cost you the game.
如果把其他人摁倒在地 我就引发战争了
If I tackle the wrong man to the ground, I could start a war.
也许没那么明显
Maybe it's less obvious.
紧张的跺脚 一阵焦虑的躁动
A nervous tic. A flutter of anxiety.
我想今晚每个人都会有他紧张的理由
I expect everyone has a reason to be nervous tonight.
我不确定
I don't know.
也有可能恰恰相反
So perhaps it's the opposite:
他没有了自然表现
A failure to behave naturally.
一个演员太专注于他的表演
An actor so consumed with his performance…
以至于他唯一不能表现出的
…that the one characteristic he cannot accommodate…
就是下意识反应
…is spontaneous reaction.
我的弟弟
我求你了
姐姐 原谅我
卡罗瑟 保护首相大人
Carruthers, protect the prime minister.
德国会付出代价的
Germany will pay! Mark my words!
似乎不太顺利 对吗
That doesn't bode well, does it?
看来你的象多少有点作用
Seems your bishop was of some benefit after all.
胜负还不明朗
The game is still young.
其实胜负已经有定数了
Actually, it's in its adolescence.
我们还有很多人
There are more of us!
德国必须付出代价
Germany will pay!
不留后患
No loose ends.
他怎么回事
What happened to him?
我是个医生 是医生
I'm a doctor. A doctor!
出了什么事
What happened?
是箭毒
Curare.
他这是怎么了
What's wrong with him?
他中毒了
It's poison.
救救他
Do something!
Doctor, do something!
快来人啊 我的天哪 快救救他
我想你刚丢了最重要的棋子
I think you've just lost your most valuable piece.
制胜的策略有时候需要做出牺牲
But a winning strategy sometimes necessitates sacrifice.
战争被避免了
A war has been averted.
我不这么认为
Mm. Oh, I disagree.
怎么说
How so?
你不觉得奇怪吗 你所发出的电报
Didn't you find it strange that the telegram you sent…
居然没有给我带来任何的阻挠
…didn't inspire any action to stop me?
听着 在潜意识的深处
You see, hidden within the unconscious…
隐藏着对冲突的无限渴望
…is an insatiable desire for conflict.
所以与其说你反对我
So you're not fighting me
不如说是在反对人的天性
so much as you are the human condition.
我想要的无非是拥有子弹和绷带
AII I want to do is own the bullets and the bandages.
工业时代的战争是不可避免的
War on an industrial scale is inevitable.
不要几年他们自己就会打起来
Theyl do it themselves within a few years.
我所要做的就是等待
AII I have to do is wait.
我喜欢瑞士
I like Switzerland.
他们尊重个人的隐私
They respect a man's privacy here.
尤其是那些有钱人
Particularly if he has a fortune.
象吃马 将军
Bishop takes knight. Check.
棋已经下完了
The game is over.
去把肩伤治一下吧
You should get that shoulder looked at.
关于你那些财富
About that fortune of yours.
我恐怕它已经明显地缩水了
I believe it's just been substantially reduced.
王向车两格
King to rook two.
我听过几次你的讲座
I attended several of your lectures.
这是运动公式 在我的书里也提到过
The equations of motion, which you will find in my book.
释放这些爆炸所需要的能量就是
The energy that is required to release these explosions is…
我是在奥斯陆第一次看到你的小手册的
It was in Oslo when I first caught a glimpse of your little notebook…
邦德街斯迈森出品的红色皮面本
…red leather-bound from Smythson of Bond Street.
车向王车移动三格 将军
Rook to king's rook three. Check.
象向车三格
Bishop to rook three.
我一开始不知道它的重要性
Its importance was not fully apparent to me…
直到我观察了你喂鸽子的小爱好
…until I observed your penchant for feeding pigeons.
然后我想到经营如此庞大的产业
Then it occurred that with an empire so enormous…
就算是你也要做一点记录
…even you must keep a record of it somewhere.
象吃象
Bishop takes bishop.
车向象四格
Rook to bishop four.
接下来就是要弄到这手册
I then only required the notebook itself.
这并不容易
You didn't make it easy.
先生 您的外套 谢谢
拿行李就行了
Just the bags.
为此我承受了相当的痛苦
I would need to endure a considerable amount of pain.
迈克罗夫特
Mycroft…
女王陛下的密探
care of Her Majesty's Secret Service.
但是这本子上的内容无疑是加密的
But the notebook would undoubtedly be encoded,
我该如何破解呢
so how then to break the code?
车吃车
Rook takes rook.
兵吃车
Pawn takes rook.
象向象七格
Bishop to bishop seven.
后 吃掉马和兵
Queen takes knight pawn.
那本《室内园艺的艺术》
Does The Art of Domestic Horticulture
你还记得吗
mean anything to you?
为什么像你这么细心的人有了这本书
How could a man as meticulous as you own such a book…
但是窗台上的花却无人打理
…yet completely neglect the flowers in his own window box?
这太荒谬了
Irony abounds.
别担心 它很安全
Never mind, it's safe,
在伦敦
in London…
而我的同事正对其善加利用
…where my colleagues are making good use of it.
（室内园艺的艺术）
欧洲最不可一世的犯罪首脑的全部家产
The most formidable criminal mind in Europe has just had all his money stolen…
刚被伦敦警局史上最没用的督察给抄走了
…by perhaps the most inept inspector in the history of Scotland Yard.
能给我倒杯茶吗
Any chance of a cup of tea?
0403号箱子
Box 0403.
有了
Check.
0801号箱子
Box 0801.
还有多少
How much more is there?
第二页结束了
That's the end of page two.
第三页
Page three.
（当心你钓的鱼）
他会把钱匿名捐给 战争遗孀和孤儿基金会
He'll be making an anonymous donation to the Widows and Orphans of War Fund.
象向象八格 将军
Bishop to bishop eight. Discover check.
很不巧的 死棋
And, incidentally, mate.
我的肩膀好像受伤了 帮我一把好吗
I seem to have injured my shoulder. Would you mind?
非常乐意
Be my pleasure.
等我们这里的事情办完之后
Once we've concluded our business here…
你知道我一定会
…it's important you know…
找到最有创意的方式来了结那个医生
…I shall endeavor to find the most creative of endings for the doctor.
和他的妻子
And his wife.
他的优势是我有伤在身
His advantage, my injury.
我的优势是他急火攻心
My advantage, his rage.
他的攻击很鲁莽 却也很犀利
Incoming assault feral, but experienced.
利用出拳间隙 予以反击
Use his momentum to counter.
别傻了 你真以为只有你会玩这一套吗
Come now. You really think you're the only one who can play this game.
抓住手臂 攻击他的弱点
Trap arm. Target weakness.
紧接着重拳挥击
Follow with haymaker.
真不愧是当年剑桥的拳击冠军
Ah. There we find the boxing champion of Cambridge.
反击有效 但容易看穿
Competent, but predictable.
现在轮到我来回应了
Now allow me to reply.
火力难以为继 要调整策略
Arsenal running dry. Adjust strategy.
伤势的影响开始体现
Wound taking its toll.
如我担心的 肩伤让我无力防守
As I feared. Injury makes defense untenable.
预期结果 会越来越糟糕
Prognosis increasingly negative.
让我们别再浪费彼此的时间了
Let's not waste any more of one another's time.
结果我们心里都清楚
We both know how this ends.
推理完毕 必死无疑
Conclusion, inevitable.
除非
Unless…
故事的尾声无需赘述
A few words may suffice to tell the little that remains.
任何寻找尸体的努力都以失败而告终
Any attempt at finding the bodies was absolutely hopeless.
因此在那
And so there…
宏伟雄壮的漩涡和奔腾不息
…deep down in that dreadful caldron of swirling water
的浪花之下
and seething foam…
将永远长眠着…
…will lie for all time…
一个最危险的罪犯
…the most dangerous criminal…
和那个时代最伟大的正义先锋
…and the foremost champion of the law of their generation.
在我心中他永远都是
I shall ever regard him as the best…
我见过的最优秀最智慧的人
…and the wisest man whom I have ever known.
约翰
John.
嗯
Mm-hm.
你该收拾东西了
You should probably pack.
现在两点半 马车四点就来了
It's half past 2…and the carriage is coming at 4.
嗯
Mm.
我们会在布莱顿度过美妙的一周
It's gonna be a beautiful week in Brighton.
一定很开心
Yes, it'll be fun.
我真的非常期待
I'm looking forward to it.
我也非常想他
You know I miss him too…
用我的方式
…in my own way.
他肯定不希望我们成行
He would have wanted us to go.
他一定想跟我们一起去
He would have wanted to come with us.
哈德森夫人几点来接格莱斯顿
When's Mrs. Hudson coming for Gladstone?
应该快了
Oh, soon.
三点钟
Three o'clock.
玛丽
Mary?
这包裹是谁送来的
Who delivered this parcel?
邮递员
The postman.
以前那一个还是
The usual chap or…
看上去有点诡异
…did he look peculiar?